(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-23T00:38:47.489240",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025 睡夢 -suimu-
[Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025: Suimu]
3D新衣装お披露目
[3D New Outfit Reveal]
3D LIVE 開催 2025年11月24日
[3D Live Event: November 24, 2025]
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
不知火フレア
Shiranui Flare
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
角巻わため
Tsunomaki Watame
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025 睡夢
[Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025: Suimu]
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good night's sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
win over a peaceful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, off to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
Searching for the ideal slumber...
さあ
Now,
始めよう
let's begin.
おやすみ
Good night!
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess,
魔王の城の中で
inside the Demon King's castle.
一人閉じ込められては
With me trapped all alone,
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
I spend every single day sleeping.
今宵も
Tonight as well,
布団に入り
getting into my futon,
スヤスヤリスト生活
living a sleepy life.
枕も
My pillow
シーツも
and my sheets
硬くて眠れない
are too stiff for me to sleep!
君も寝具にしてやろうか！
Shall I turn you into bedding too?!
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good night's sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
win over a peaceful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, off to the world of dreams!
ふかふかの枕 手に入れて
After obtaining a fluffy pillow,
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal all this fatigue.
恐れず前進
March forward without fear,
ほぐせよ全身
relax your entire body!
瞼を閉じたなら
Once you close your eyelids,
すべすべのシーツの上で
on top of smooth sheets,
さあ
now,
始めよう
let's begin.
おやすみ
Good night!
ノンレム睡眠 レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess.
悲鳴が響く夜に
On a night when screams echo,
一人で檻を抜け出し
I sneak out of my cage alone.
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
Today, I'm heading out for a stroll again.
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming many trials,
新たな寝具の元へ
I search for new bedding.
もっと
More...
エネマグまで
...even into enemy magma,
猛毒で
...and deadly poison,
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if it kills me!
城ごと寝具にしてやろうか！
Shall I turn the whole castle into bedding?!
掴めよ快眠
Seize a good night's sleep!
疲れで安眠
Sleep soundly from fatigue!
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, off to the other side of dreams!
ハイテック目覚まし手に入れて
Getting a high-tech alarm clock,
気持ちよく目覚めたい
I want to wake up feeling great!
まだまだ前進
Still moving forward!
華麗に変身
A splendid transformation!
ごはんを食べたなら
Once I've finished eating my meal,
魔法のベッドにダイブして
I'll dive straight into a magical bed!
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
Now then, let's begin. Good night!
明日はもっと
Tomorrow, even more...
今日よりずっと
...and much more than today...
いい夢見れるかな
...I wonder if I can have sweet dreams.
フワフワの羽根に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers,
ココロゆくまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content.
目指せよ快眠
Aim for a good night's sleep!
勝ち取れ安眠
Win yourself some peaceful sleep!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, off to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
In search of the perfect slumber...
さあ 始めよう おやすみ
...now then, let's begin. Good night!
もうあと5分 おやすみ
Just five more minutes... Good night!
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠 ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep, Non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
スヤァ
Zzz...
ふぅー、はい！
Phew! Alright!
こんまっする！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
Konmassuru! I'm Shirogane Noel, from Hololive's 3rd Generation!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming to my live concert today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！
And here is the hashtag for today!
白銀ノエル生誕祭2025！たくさんスクショして、SNSに投稿してください！
#ShiroganeNoelBirthdayCelebration2025! Take lots of screenshots and post them on social media!
今日のライブのテーマなんですが、見ての通りね、睡眠・安眠・癒やしライブとなっております。
As for the theme of today's live, as you can see, it's a \"Sleep, Slumber, and Healing\" live concert.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくので、ぜひ皆さんも、盛り上がってください！
It's going to get more exciting toward the second half, so please get hyped up with me!
てな感じで、1曲目は『快眠！安眠！スヤリスト生活』を歌わせていただきました！
And with that, I sang \"Kaimin! Anmin! Syaristo Seikatsu\" as my first song!
あの、曲中のね、あの団長、踊りながら変身したシーンがありましたけど、
So, during the song, there was a scene where I transformed while dancing, but...
わかった？わかったっていうか、みんな気づいてる？ていうか、
Did you get it? Or rather, did everyone notice? Actually,
おメイクがちょっと変わりました！お気づきでしょうか？
My makeup has changed a little! Did you notice?
まあ具体的にね、どういうところが変わったかと言いますと、
To be specific about what exactly changed...
あの、髪の毛がですね、あの、サラサラによりなりました！
My hair has become much silkier and smoother!
サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、わかるかな？ほら、サラサラ！
It's so silky, especially from the back. Can you tell? Look, so silky!
もう本当にいつでもシャンプーのCM待ってます、てな感じでサラサラになったのと、
Honestly, I'm ready for a shampoo commercial anytime! That's how silky it is. And...
あとおメイクもね、あの、ちょっと変わっております。色んなね表情が出来るようになったんですけど、
...my makeup has also changed a little. I can make various expressions now, but...
えっと、なんか、なんか団長、ノエちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってみて。
Let's see... Say something that would make me get angry at you.
うんうん。え、何？「ちょっと太った？」
Uh-huh. What was that? \"Did you gain a bit of weight?\"
むっ！何？太ってないよ！最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！てな感じで、
Hmph! What? I didn't gain weight! I've been working hard on my diet lately! Like that,
前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、マイルド怒りになりました！はい！
...before, it felt like I was seriously angry, but now it's a mild anger! Yes!
ていう感じで、あの、ちょっとね、色んな表情が出来るようになったので、それも踏まえて、
So, since I can make a lot of different expressions now, keeping that in mind,
あの、ライブ見てくれると嬉しいです。そして！
...I'd be happy if you keep watching the live stream. And!
ま、ノエちゃんも変わったんですけど、この変わったね、お姿で、さらに！
While my model has changed, with this new look, there's even more!
本日のステージはこちらです！
Here is today's stage!
え、すごいね、全景！わあ！なんか本当に癒やしって感じだよね。もう本当に綺麗に、はい、作っていただきました。
Wow, look at the full view! It really gives off a healing vibe, doesn't it? They made it so beautifully.
ま、ここのね、周り？そう、周りね、これ雲？雲の海みたいな感じで、ぷかぷかってなっています。ええ！
And the surrounding area here... is this a cloud? It feels like a sea of clouds, floating gently. Yeah!
そしてね、ま、こうやってね、雲の海から、上もね、すごい！綺麗！
And looking up from this sea of clouds, the sky is also amazing! So pretty!
なんか飾りが、ぐるぐるぐるぐるっと回っておりますので、
The decorations are spinning around and around, so...
いや、なんかね、あの、これからちょっとゲストパートとかもあるんですけど、
...well, we have some guest segments coming up later,
なんか、それに合わせて色々と変わっていくみたいなので、ぜひ楽しみにしてみてください。
...and it seems the stage will change along with them, so please look forward to it.
それでは次の曲、レッツゴー！
Without further ado, let's head to the next song! Let's go!
僕は今 夢旅の中
Right now, I am in the middle of a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Flying to that star island,
飛んでゆける
I can make it there.
手のりウタうたう
With the singing dream-eater on my palm,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater...
君のそばにも
To your side as well,
辿り着ける
I'll make my way.
ユメクイ
[Title: Dream-Eater]
最初に描いた
The dream I first drew,
夢を思い出せなくなったのは
that I can no longer remember...
大人になったから？
Is it because I grew up?
右か左かで
Unable to choose right or left,
いつまでも迷って
forever wandering.
太陽が反転するまで
We kept talking until the sun flipped over,
喋り込んだ
and went down.
一つだけ
Just one thing...
ポケットに入れてきたもの
I've kept in my pocket:
おっきな
this big, huge...
この愛をもって
love of mine.
僕は今 夢旅の中
Right now, I'm on a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Flying to that star island,
飛んでゆける
I can make it there.
手のりウタうたう
With the singing dream-eater on my palm,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater...
君のそばにも
To your side as well,
辿り着ける
I'll make my way.
カラフルな靄に
Captured by a colorful haze,
心を奪われ
it stole my heart away,
ちょっとしたことに
and over the smallest things,
つまずいた
I stumbled.
すりむいたとこに
On my scraped knees,
君がくれたのは
what you gave me...
はずかしいくらいの
was an almost embarrassingly...
可愛らしい絆創膏
cute band-aid.
叶えるたびに
Every time a dream comes true,
食いつくすユメクイ
the dream-eater devours it.
叶えるたびに
And each time they do,
また夢を見る
I dream once again,
いくつになっても
no matter how old I get.
僕は今 夢旅の中
Right now, I'm on a dream journey.
寄り道して
Taking a little detour,
プレゼントを見つける
to find a present for you.
手のりウタうたう
With the singing dream-eater on my palm,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater...
描いた未来に
In the future I envisioned,
君がいつもいる
you are always there.
僕は今 夢旅の中
Right now, I'm on a dream journey.
あの星の島までも
Flying to that star island,
飛んでゆける
I can make it there.
手のりウタうたう
With the singing dream-eater on my palm,
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater...
君のそばにも
To your side as well,
辿り着ける
I'll make my way.
君のそばでずっと夢を見る
I'll dream forever by your side.
半端ないぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
No half-measures, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
限界突破ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
毎日半端ないぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Every day is amazing, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa!
限界突破ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
明日の私に幸あれ
May luck be with tomorrow's me!
最適温度
Optimal temperature...
塞ぎこむゴースト
Depressing ghosts...
八百万の 嫌な外的要素
Eight million unpleasant external factors.
何の気ないと
Casually...
超あっけらかんと
And completely care-free.
悪気もなく邪魔する等価の
Saying bye-bye to anyone...
誰かさんにバイバイ
Who mindlessly gets in my way.
自分時間 堕落タイム確保
Securing my personal slacking-off time!
17時〜9時は死守マスト
Must strictly defend 5:00 PM to 9:00 AM!
さらに愛（i）や舞（my）も忘れずに とどのつまり
And don't forget "i" (love) or "my" (dance) either, in the end.
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ
Overworking is strictly off-limits!
注意喚起もしてますよ
This is your friendly warning!
ねえ楽して 苦（ku）なくして
Hey, make it easy, remove the pain...
生きてくって難しいな
Living life is so tough.
だって 安定 裏技 一夜漬け
After all, stability, shortcuts, and cramming...
甘い蜜に溺れ流る やー！
Drowning in sweet nectar as we float along. Yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
When I'm sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたかったら遊ぶ
If I want to play, I play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I'm hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない？
If I'm sad, isn't it fine to cry?
明日の私のために今日も なんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow get through today!
明日も頑張らなくていいように 頑張るのさ
I work hard today so I don't have to tomorrow!
怠惰じゃないや これ多分そうだ
This isn't laziness, at least I don't think so.
なんだかんだやることやっています！
I'm actually getting things done, one way or another!
What? Eh? What?
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから
I don't really care if nobody notices.
私には私のマイルール
I have my own set of rules.
明日楽するためには はいチーズ
To make tomorrow easy, say cheese!
意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースのある
Surprisingly, with a bit of love and peace...
毎日を生きてたいのです
I just want to live each day.
Don't be shy ドキドキしたい
Don't be shy, I want some excitement.
Let me shine
明日天気になれ To be excite
Hope it's sunny tomorrow, to be excited!
心もっと踊りたい
I want my heart to dance even more!
月 火 水 木 金 土 日 げん！
Mon, Tue, Wed, Thu, Fri, Sat, Sun, let's go!
辛くなったら歌う
If things get tough, I sing.
むかついたら愚痴る
If I get annoyed, I vent.
やりたいようにやる
I do things my way.
それができたら苦労しないわ
If it were that easy, I wouldn't be struggling!
常に一喜一憂
Constantly swinging from joy to sorrow...
してりゃ何期あろうと持たんから
I wouldn't last, no matter how many lives I have!
適当にセーブしリスクは回避
So I'll save moderately and avoid risks.
まぁ頑張るのさ
Well, I'll still do my best.
適当にとまでは言うまいが
I won't go so far as to say slacking off...
まぁ頑張るのさ
But I'll still do my best.
夢の中では...
In my dreams...
ずっとぐーたらしてやるんだ...
I'm going to laze around forever...
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなく 明日の私のため保存
Not for anyone else's sake, but for tomorrow's me!
Fight!
楽するために苦しいことも 乗り越えちゃうんだからね
Because I'll even overcome the painful things just to make it easy later!
Fight!
やりたくないことやらないために やりたくないことやれ
Do the things you don't want to do, so you don't have to do things you don't want to do!
Fight!
あれ？これって結構頑張れてる
Huh? I'm actually doing pretty well...
私とっても偉いじゃないか！
Aren't I super awesome?!
自分時間 堕落タイム確保
Securing my personal slacking-off time!
17時〜9時は死守マスト保存
Must strictly defend 5:00 PM to 9:00 AM!
さらに愛（i）や舞（my）も忘れずに とどのつまり
And don't forget "i" (love) or "my" (dance) either, in the end.
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ
Overworking is strictly off-limits!
注意喚起もしてますよ
This is your friendly warning!
ねえ楽して 苦（ku）なくして保存
Hey, make it easy, remove the pain...
生きてくって難しいな
Living life is so tough.
安定 裏技 一夜漬け
Stability, shortcuts, and cramming...
甘い蜜に溺れ流る やー！
Drowning in sweet nectar as we float along. Yeah!
眠くなったら寝る
When I'm sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたかったら遊ぶ
If I want to play, I play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
If I'm hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
If I'm happy, I laugh.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない？
If I'm sad, isn't it fine to cry?
明日の私のために今日も なんとか頑張るのさ
For the sake of tomorrow's me, I'll somehow get through today!
明日も頑張らなくていいように 頑張るのさ
I work hard today so I don't have to tomorrow!
半端ないぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
No half-measures, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
限界突破ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
毎日半端ないぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Every day is amazing, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa!
限界突破ぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱらっぱ
Breaking limits, pa-ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa ra-ppa!
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, go invent!
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, go invent!
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and go invent!
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I am going to become the King of Inventors!
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, go invent!
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, go invent!
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and go invent!
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I am going to become the King of Inventors!
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison's self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison's self-esteem.
踊るエジソン自尊心
Dancing Edison's self-esteem.
歌うエジソンジソン心
Singing Edison's self-esteem.
幼少期の頃から家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
Ever since childhood, the music playing at home was House music.
サブスクのプレイリスト聞いて曲ディグったならクラブでDJ
Listening to streaming playlists, digging up tracks, then DJing at the club.
パソコン開いたならDTM ソフトはAbleton Live
Opening my laptop for DTM, my software of choice is Ableton Live.
だけど今作りたいのは蓄音機
But what I want to make now is a gramophone.
サークルでの宴会芸
College club banquet performance,
ノリで始めたバンドで
with a band we started just for fun.
まぐれでバズってメジャーデビュー
By a fluke, we went viral and made our major debut.
なぜか今はしがないミュージシャン
Somehow, now I'm just a measly musician.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem,
歌うエジソン ジソン心
singing Edison, self-esteem.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem,
歌うエジソン ジソン心
singing Edison, self-esteem.
YouTubeを見て得る 1％のひらめき
Watching YouTube to get that 1% spark...
インスピレーション
...of inspiration,
SNS通して繋がる
connecting through social media...
発明家のコミュニケーション
...for communication among inventors.
インスタ映え狙った投稿
Making posts aimed at looking good on Instagram,
Webニュースで情報収集
gathering information from web news.
間違いなくこれからの時代来るのは
Without a doubt, what's coming next is...
活動写真
...motion pictures.
いや、絶対来ると思うんだけどな
I mean, I'm absolutely sure it's coming, though...
踊る暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, go invent something.
歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to sing, go invent something.
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
Cancel your live bookings and go invent something.
そんな発明王にオレはなる
That's the kind of King of Inventors I will become!
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem,
歌うエジソン ジソン心
singing Edison, self-esteem.
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, self-esteem,
歌うエジソン ジソン心
singing Edison, self-esteem.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today won't end in goodbye like this,
手をとってくれたなら
if only you would take my hand.
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
On a night when even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I will take you away.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
Even if we are far apart, for instance,
手を繋いでいられるような 奇跡のような
a miracle-like story where we can stay connected...
話をしよう
...let's talk about it.
窓は開けておいて
Please leave your window open.
今日までを思い出して
Remembering everything up to today,
一つ一つ並べたら
as I line them up one by one,
明日の雨が気になりだして
I start to worry about tomorrow's rain,
どうも眠れないみたいだ
and it seems I just can't fall asleep.
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change,
変わらなきゃいけないことも
and things that must change as well,
少し忘れたまま
leaving them slightly forgotten,
窓の外を眺めていたんだ
I was gazing out the window.
あぁ 雨が降り出すその前に
Ah, before the rain begins to fall,
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it all the way to you.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
そしてこのまま遠くへと行こう
And just like this, let's go far away.
手をとってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll take my hand.
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
Through the night where even secrets fall asleep,
君と
with you,
泳いでいくよ
I'll swim on.
街の明かりが消える度に笑って
Laughing each time the city lights fade,
路地裏で抱き合おう
let's embrace in the back alleys.
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう
Let's talk about silly things.
窓は開けておいて
Please leave your window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
Lovely things,
無くせないものを
and things we cannot afford to lose—
教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
what taught them to me was a night like tonight.
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた
We wove them together by layering the nights...
私たちに響く音
...into a sound that resonates within us.
夜が来る度に
Every time the night comes,
心が躍ってしまうのは
my heart leaps with excitement,
また一つ重なっていくから
because we are layering yet another memory.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I closed my eyes...
今夜 私たちだけで眠ろう
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us.
誰にも言わないで
Please don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつく その少し前に
Just a little before you fall asleep,
名前を呼んで
call my name.
叶わない願いに 胸は痛んで
My heart aches from an unfulfilled wish,
うつむいてしまうけど
and I end up looking down, but...
誰もいない 街へ誘いに行くから
I'll come invite you to a town with no one else around.
今日はこのまま さよならじゃないよ
Today doesn't end in goodbye like this.
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も 眠りにつくような夜に
on a night when even secrets seem to fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you away.
それは例えば 遠く離れてたって
Even if we are, for instance, far apart,
手をつないでいられるような 奇跡のような
we can still hold hands like a miracle.
話をしよう
Let's talk.
窓はあけておいて<
Leave the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや
Dear things, or...
無くせないものを
things we cannot lose...
教えてくれたのは
What taught me that was...
今日みたいな 夜を重ねて
layering nights like tonight,
織り上げてきた 私たちに響く音
weaving the sound that resonates within us.
響く言葉...
The words that resonate...
はーい！ということで
Alright! So,
皆さん！今回のライブ、なんと新衣装が...
everyone! For this live show, my new outfit is...
ぽぽぽぽぽぽぽん！ありましたー！
Pop-pop-pop-pop! Ta-da!
ということで、あの、びっくりしたかな？びっくりしたんじゃないかなと思います！
So, um, were you surprised? I think you might have been surprised!
あの、こちらね、すごい、あの、きらびやかな衣装となっているんですけど
Um, this is a very, like, gorgeous outfit, but...
ちょっと今、スクショの、撮る...
right now, for the screenshots...
えい！
Yah!
可愛いですか？
Is it cute?
ぜひ、あの、ハッシュタグでね、あの、ぜひ呟いてください。可愛いでしょう？
Please tweet about it using the hashtag. It's cute, right?
何やらね、この後、ちょっと衣装のね、色々、あの、細部まで、ちょっと見る機会がありそうな予感がするので
For some reason, I have a feeling there will be an opportunity to see the details of this outfit later...
一旦ね、スクショだけ。お願いします。
so for now, just the screenshots. Please!
そして、あとこちらね、見て？
Also, look at this, okay?
手首に、ぷらぷらって紐があるんだけど、これね、取れます！
There are loose ribbons hanging from my wrists, and these can be detached!
じゃ、とってもらおうかな。えい！えい！ということで、はい、取れます。
Let me have them taken off. Yah! Yah! There we go, yes, they come off.
こちらのバージョンもスクショ、撮ってもらおう。えい！可愛いですか？
Let's get screenshots of this version too. Yah! Is it cute?
ぴゃあー！ねえ、すごい可愛らしい衣装。
Pyaa! It's such a lovely outfit.
ちょっとね、あの、ドキドキするんですが、うん。
I'm a bit nervous, but yes.
いや、なんか、でもちょっと一人、寂しいな。なんか、だいにさん...
But, somehow, I feel a bit lonely on my own. Maybe, Daini-san...
あ！あれ、可愛い！おお、なんか、むずむずしてる。どうした？どうした？
Ah! Look, how cute! Oh, he's squirming. What's wrong? What's wrong?
きゃあー！だいにさん飛んできた！
Kyaa! Daini-san flew over here!
そんなに、のえちゃんに会いたかったんかな？可愛いね。
Did you want to see Noe-chan that much? So cute!
いっぱいスクショ撮ってな。うーん、だいにさんとのツーショット！可愛い。
Take lots of screenshots, okay? Mmh, a two-shot with Daini-san! So cute.
え、何何？あ、今日は安眠テーマで、あ、心地よい、あ、なるほどね。ん？
Eh, what's that? Ah, today's theme is peaceful sleep, so it's cozy... ah, I see. Hm?
曲のリクエスト？あ、子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい。あ、そうなのだいにさん？
A song request? Ah, you want to hear a lullaby-like song. Ah, is that so, Daini-san?
じゃあ、せっかくだいにさん来てくれたし、一緒にじゃあ子守唄、うん。歌うよ、歌う、なんか、ちょっとついてきて！一緒に、行くよ！おら！おらーい！
Well, since Daini-san is here, let's sing a lullaby together. Yes. I'll sing! Come along with me! Let's go together! Alright, here we go!
小さき 人の子よ
Little human child...
森へ 迷い込んだ
who wandered into the forest...
大きな...
Big...
大きなこの羽が
These giant wings...
ぼうやは見えないのね
...you're unable to see them, little boy.
なにも知らない
Oh, those round little cheeks...
まあるいほっぺよ
...that don't know a thing.
ねむれや ねむれ
Sleep now, sleep.
しずかな水辺においで
Come on down by the quiet waterside.
ぼうやの夢は
Your dreams...
竜の背に運ばれて
...will be carried upon a dragon's back...
山の向こうへ消える
...to disappear beyond the mountains.
よろずの子らも
Many, many children...
ならんでねむる
...sleep side-by-side.
七つ数えたら
When I count to seven...
仲良くねむってく
...they will sleep happily together.
なにも見えない
Oh, those tiny eyes...
小さなおめめよ
...that can't see a thing.
ねむれや ねむれ
Sleep now, sleep.
そよぐ草むらへおいで
Come on down by the swaying brush.
ぼうやの夢は
Your dreams...
母さんを探しては
...will go searching for their mother...
空の向こうへ帰る
...returning to a place beyond the sky.
竜の背に運ばれて
Carried upon a dragon's back...
山の向こうへ消える
...they'll disappear beyond the mountains.
プラネタリウム
[Planetarium]
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく 子どもの声
The crescent moon shows its face, and children's voices fade away...
遠く遠く この空のどこかに 君はいるんだろう
...somewhere far, far away in this sky, you must be there.
夏の終わりに2人で抜け出した この公園で見つけた
We snuck out together at the end of summer and found in this park...
あの星座 何だか 覚えてる?
...that constellation. Do you remember what it was?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I follow my memories...
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
...wanting to see the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がパッと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks suddenly burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to go to you, I want to run to you right now.
まっ暗で何も見えない 怖くても大丈夫
Even if it's pitch black and I can't see anything, even if I'm scared, I'll be fine.
数えきれない星空が 今もずっとここにあるんだよ
The countless stars in the night sky are still here, always.
泣かないよ
I won't cry...
...き君と見た 綺麗な空だったから
...since it was the beautiful sky I saw with you.
あの道まで
Up to that road...
響く靴の音が
the sound of echoing shoes...
耳に残る
...lingers in my ears.
大きな自分の
Staring at my large shadow,
影を見つめて想うのでしょう
I wonder what you are thinking.
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
Even though nothing should have changed,
せつない気持ちふくらんでく
these painful feelings keep swelling up.
どんなに想ったって君はもういない
No matter how much I long for you, you're no longer here.
行きたいよ 君のそばに
I want to go to your side,
小さくても 小さくても
even if it's just a little bit.
1番に君が好きだよ
I love you the most,
強くいられる
it keeps me strong.
願いを流れ星に
I quietly made a wish
そっと唱えてみたけれど
upon a shooting star, but...
泣かないよ 届くだろう
...I won't cry. Surely it will reach...
綺麗な空に
...into the beautiful sky.
会えなくても記憶をたどって
Even if we can't meet, I'll trace my memories,
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
wanting to see the same happiness as you.
あの香りとともに花火がぱっと開く
Along with that scent, the fireworks burst open.
行きたいよ 君のところへ
I want to go to where you are,
小さな手をにぎりしめて
clenching my small hands.
泣きたいよ それはそれは
I want to cry, because it was...
綺麗な空だった
...such a beautiful sky.
願いを流れ星に
I quietly made a wish
そっと唱えてみたけれど
upon a shooting star, but...
泣きたいよ 届かない想いを
I want to cry, sending my unreachable feelings...
この空に...
...into this sky...
[曲名] RELAY
[Song: RELAY]
もう何十回 もう何百回も 震むソラ見上げて
Dozens of times, hundreds of times, looking up at the trembling sky,
辿り着いた場所が 運命のダイヤモンド
the place I finally reached is the diamond of fate.
何千回 もう何万回も 涙流したきみへ
To you, who shed tears thousands, tens of thousands of times,
ねえ 諦められたことはあったっけ？
tell me, did you ever give up?
「憧れ＝限界」だから もういらないよ
Since "longing equals limits," I don't need it anymore.
そこに留まるなんて もったいないでしょ？
Isn't it a waste to just stay in one place?
それぞれの物語 交差する瞬間を
The moment when our respective stories intersect...
見つめる意味は
...the meaning of gazing upon it is...
放った夢だけ 大きな弧を描いて
...only the dreams we set free, drawing a giant arc.
はち切れそうな 煌めきを
With a radiance that seems ready to burst,
消えることなく どこまででも
it will never fade, going on forever.
世界の向こうに 届けよう
Let's deliver it to the other side of the world!
終わることのない この胸の衝動は
This endless impulse in my chest...
どうしたって どうしても ぼくを呼んでいた
...was calling out to me no matter what.
だから その先へと 走り続ける
That's why I'll keep running beyond that,
次へ 次へ
forward and forward!
妄想だった 中途半端な
It was a delusion, carrying my half-baked...
不甲斐なさ抱えて
...and miserable self,
立ち尽くしていた
I stood there frozen in place.
通り雨はプレリュード
The passing shower is a prelude.
何千回 もう何万回も
Thousands, or even tens of thousands of times,
挑み続けたきみへ
to you who kept on challenging.
ねえ 聴かせてよ
Hey, let me hear it,
「夢は叶うんだ」って
singing "dreams do come true."
「諦め＝完敗」ならば
If giving up means utter defeat,
絶対にないよ
that will never happen.
だれに邪魔されようと
No matter who tries to get in our way,
ためらわないで
don't hesitate.
託された情熱を
The passion entrusted to us,
落とさずにつないでく
we will pass it on without letting it drop.
そう 最後まで
Yes, until the very end!
フラッグに誓い
Swearing upon the flag,
雄々しくはためいて
fluttering valiantly.
鳴り止まないファンファーレ
An endless fanfare...
いつも心に
...has always been flowing...
流れていた
...deep inside my heart.
遠い未来へ
Toward the distant future,
祈るように
as if praying,
忘れられない
we chase after...
あの日の後悔を
...the regrets of those unforgettable days...
追いかけて 追いかけて
...chasing and chasing after them...
滑り込んだ この想い
...these feelings finally slipped through.
青いソラに
Into the blue sky,
ふと溢れていった
they suddenly overflowed,
遠く 遠く
far and wide.
終わらない 終わらない 仕事が山積み終わらない
No end in sight, no end in sight! A mountain of work that never ends!
止まらない 止まらない それでも時間は止まらない
Can't stop, can't stop! Even so, time just keeps ticking by!
Yo, Yo!
ヘトヘト 溜まり溜まった ヘイト
Exhausted, with pent-up frustration piling up.
千番勝負 誓い ズバッと コンボ メイズに金属バット Swing!
A thousand-round match, a promise, a sharp combo! Swinging a metal bat in a maze!
今日も手一杯 今日も手一杯
My hands are full again today, so full again today!
No more... もう無理！ ギミギミ ぎゅーして！ I see
No more... I can't take it! Gimme gimme a hug! I see...
奔走 Anytime 奔走 Anytime
Rushing around anytime, rushing around anytime...
はぁーあ ハメ外す手前で Energy すっからかん
Sigh... just before letting loose, my energy is completely drained.
自分自身に厳しすぎちゃう
I'm always way too hard on myself.
すぐさまヘラヘラ優等生 さっぱり足りない順応性
Instantly acting like a smiley, perfect student, with absolutely zero adaptability.
自分自身としっかりサシで向き合う
I need to face myself properly, one-on-one.
一番必要なものは トレビアン
What I need most of all is...
ご褒美頂戴 Wah!
...something très bien! Give me a reward, wah!
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to this frantic, hectic rhythm!
ドレミファの音に乗りに来らん？ Wah!
Won't you come ride on the Do-Re-Mi-Fa notes? Wah!
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰め込みゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Don't pack things so tight! Let's get more and more freedom!
Uh...
オーライ オーライ
All right, all right!
好きなもの食べ放題 お気楽に過ごしますのね
All-you-can-eat of my favorite foods! I'm going to spend my time at ease, you know.
ほらもっともっと頂戴 膨大 Get ready
Hey, give me more and more, an enormous amount! Get ready!
タフボディです たまに空回り
I've got a tough body, though sometimes I spin my wheels.
満ち足りた日越す胸張りお大盛り
Standing tall with a generous extra serving, to get through fulfilling days.
いらない まやかしの甘やかし
I don't need any fake pampering.
ハッピーになるため歌おう 声高らかに Yeah!
Let's sing to be happy, raising our voices loud! Yeah!
自分自身がやっぱり一番
As expected, being yourself is the absolute best!
理性と欲望が平行線 望みは幸せエンドレス
Reason and desire run parallel, but my wish is endless happiness.
自分自身としっかり付き合う
I will get along with myself properly.
我慢は体に毒だよ トレビアン
Bottling things up is bad for your health! It's...
ご褒美頂戴 Wah!
...très bien! Give me a reward, wah!
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to this frantic, hectic rhythm!
ドレミファの音に乗りに来らん？ Wah!
Won't you come ride on the Do-Re-Mi-Fa notes? Wah!
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰め込みゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Don't pack things so tight! Let's get more and more freedom!
1 2 の 3 はい！
One, two, three, go!
窮屈な服に非平衡ストレス 状態異常系から解放
Unbalanced stress in tight clothes, breaking free from all status ailments!
もっともっと もっともっと まだまだ足りない
More, more, more, more, it's still not enough!
本日は欲望解放パーリナイ
Today is a party night to release our desires!
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアン
Très bien!
ご褒美
Give me
頂戴
my reward!
てんてこ舞うようなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Say goodbye to this chaotic rhythm!
ドレミファの音に go ride
Go ride on the sound of Do-Re-Mi-Fa!
ぎゅうぎゅうと詰めちゃダメ どんどんフリーダム
Don't pack it in too tight, keep getting more freedom!
ぎゅうぎゅう詰めの ご褒美 どんどん 好きになる
I'll love these packed rewards more and more!
フィーバー！
Fever!
はっ！
Hah!
はっ！はっ！
Hah! Hah!
おいで！おいで！誘惑の Dance again
Come on! Come on! Tempting dance again
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on in! Come on! To Kaguya's castle
出会いがあやつるミステリー
An encounter that weaves a mystery
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona
踊ろう！踊ろう！終わらない Dance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! To the never-ending dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! At Kaguya's castle
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
Laser beams cutting through the night sky
私と見てよ？
Won't you watch with me?
まばゆい星が照らす想い
A blinding star illuminates my feelings
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight's dream last forever
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow
にぱっ
Nipa!
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I'm the princess of red roses
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently swept away
そっと囁いて 意味ありげに目をそらす
Whispering softly, turning my eyes away suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are my white moon knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
My hand is still hot where you touched it
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let me go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
We call this miracle love, don't we?
はい！
Hai!
はっ！
Hah!
おいで！おいで！情熱で Dance again
Come on! Come on! Passionate dance again
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on in! Come on! To Kaguya's castle
迷いを飲みこむエナジー
Energy that swallows up all hesitation
眠らぬパッショネイト
Sleepless passion
踊ろう！踊ろう！止まらない Dance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! To the unstoppable dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! At Kaguya's castle
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations
私も混ぜて？
Won't you let me join too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart swearing to the sparkling stars
儚い夢でいいわ
A fleeting dream is just fine
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow is another day
だよね
Right?
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I'm the princess of black roses
激しくさらわれたい
I want to be swept away intensely
だから微笑んで 追いかけてと目が誘う
So smile, and let your eyes invite me to chase you
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You are my black moon knight too
瞳の奥は熱い
Deep inside your eyes, it's hot
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me and hold me tight
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
This miracle calls for love, doesn't it?
一緒に行こう？
Shall we go together?
ついてきてよ
Follow me!
他の人見ちゃいや
Don't look at anyone else!
私だけを見て
Look only at me!
後悔するわよ
You'll regret it!
楽しも！
Let's have fun!
早くしなさいよ
Hurry up!
鈍いのですね
You're so slow, aren't you?
いいの？
Is that alright?
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I'm the princess of red roses
優しくさらわれたい
I want to be gently swept away
そっと囁いて意味ありげに目をそらす
Whispering softly, turning my eyes away suggestively
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are my white moon knight
触れた手がまだ熱い
My hand is still hot where you touched it
のがさずに抱きしめて
Don't let me go, hold me tight
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
We call this miracle love, don't we?
はーい！
Hi!
ということで、3期生のみんなと『輝夜の城で踊りたい』を歌って踊りましたー！
And with that, I sang and danced to "Kaguya no Shiro de Odoritai" with my fellow Gen 3 members!
イェーイ！
Yay!
のえちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Noe-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうー！わーい！ありがとう！
Thank you so much! Yay! Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃない？
Aren't you looking super cute?
え、可愛い？
Really? Am I cute?
なんか服装に対する動きが…動きがちょっと…
But your movements compared to the outfit are... a little...
ちょっとね、可愛く…
A bit, you know... I'll try to be cute...
可愛いです。あ、可愛い？
How's this? Is it cute?
可愛いー！すごいね、なんかここがめっちゃ…
So cute! Wow, this part here is really...
ここ大丈夫ですか？
Is this area allowed?!
おっぱいがお尻だよ、のえちゃん！
Your chest looks like a butt, Noe-chan!
こんなおっぱいに挨拶しちゃう…
I ended up bowing to your chest...
今日からはさ、こう話せばいいのかな？
Starting today, should I talk to you like this?
違う違う違う！それじゃあ目が合わないだろ！
No, no, no! Our eyes won't meet if you do that!
ええと、今回の衣装はね、あの、200万人記念で、はい、作っていただきました。
Um, this outfit was actually made to celebrate 2 million subscribers.
他にもね、変わったところ、今日のライブからであるんだけど…
There are also other changes starting with today's live stream...
あれ？マリンが怒ってる？
Wait, is Marine mad?
メイクは？
What about her makeup?
あ！気づいた！
Ah! You noticed!
気づいた？ということで、そうなんですよ。ちょっとメイク変わりました。
You noticed? That's right, my makeup changed slightly.
全然違う！全然違う！
It's totally different! Totally different!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありまして、ちょっとね、あの…
By the way, I have a favorite expression now...
あの、お困り顔。お困り顔がすごく可愛いの。
My troubled face. This troubled face is super cute.
お口が三角にぷりんってなってるんです。あ、本当だ！
My mouth gets all pouty and triangular! Oh, you're right!
うわー！
Whoa!
うわーじゃなかった。えーじゃあ、ちょっと衣装せっかくなんで…
Wait, that's not a "whoa". Let's show off the outfit since we're here...
下からちょっと、舐めるように…いきましょうよ！
Let's pan up from the bottom, slowly!
お靴から見ましょう、お靴から。
Let's start from the shoes, the shoes first.
おら、可愛いお靴！
Look, what cute shoes!
可愛い。ちょっとよく見せて。あ、ヒールなんだね！
They're cute. Let us see them clearly. Oh, they have heels!
普段は通常でぺったんこだから、ちょっと身長盛りました。
Since my default shoes are flat, I boosted my height a bit.
リボンが後ろ側、後ろにね。
And there are ribbons on the back, right?
そうなんです、ついてます。可愛い。いい、いい。
That's right, they're there. So cute. Nice, nice.
じゃあちょっと、舐めるように…
Now, let's pan up...
うわー！おおー！一体どんなおっぱいが…
Whoa! Oh! Just what kind of chest...
こら！こらこらこら！
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
好奇心が…ええ、こんな感じで…
Her curiosity... Yeah, like this...
え、ちょっとそんなさっさっさと終わらせないで。まだ舐め終わってない。
Wait, don't end it so quickly. We're still panning up!
あ、あー！
Ah, ah!
ここのね、ノエルがいてね。
There is a Noel here.
ノエルちゃん、ここ。皆さんご覧ください。ここのこのこのこのこのこのこのこのこのこの胸…
Noel-chan, look here. Everyone, check this out. This chest right here...
このこのこの隙間、隙間隙間！
This, this gap! The gap, the gap!
分かります？この下、乳と乳の間の…本当だ、すごいね。繋がってる。
Do you see it? Below this, between the breasts... Oh, you're right, it's amazing. They're connected!
隙間がね、ほら！うわー！大丈夫？目が！
The gap, look! Whoa! Are you okay? Your eyes!
最高の衣装だ！ありがとうございます。
It's the best costume ever! Thank you so much.
じゃ、ちょっと上見せるにあたって、このひらひら取れるから、ちょっと…
Now, to show the upper part, these frills can actually be removed...
可愛い、それ！ちょっと取ってもいい？
That's so cute! Can I take them off?
取ってみて、取ってみて！取ってください。はい！
Try taking them off! Go ahead. Here!
おおー！すっきり！バンザーイ！
Oh! So clean! Banzai!
バンザーイ！歩きやすい。え、横がどうなってるのかしら。ゆっくりくるくる回って。
Banzai! It's easier to walk. Oh, I wonder how the side looks. Spin around slowly.
くるくるくるくる…髪の毛！髪の毛ふわふわで可愛い！
Spin, spin, spin... Your hair! Your hair is so fluffy and cute!
ふわふわだよー。編み込みめっちゃ可愛い。
It's so fluffy! The braids are super cute.
お姫様。リボンがこう髪にね、こう巻き込んでる感じで。
A princess. The ribbon is woven into her hair.
そう、編み込んで。姫騎士なんでね、お姫様…なってます。
Yes, braided in. Since I'm a princess knight... I've become one.
可愛いー！
So cute!
可愛すぎる。こんなの好きになっちゃう。ちょっと距離置きたいからいつもの動きして。
Too cute. I'm going to fall for you. I need to get some distance, so do your usual movements.
待ってた、待てた、待てた！
Iwas waiting for that!
あ、なんか好きじゃなくなった？危ない危ない、恋するところだった。
Oh, you don't like me anymore? Close call, I was about to fall in love.
いや、でも本当に、可愛い衣装、本当にありがとうございました。おめでとうー！
But really, thank you so much for this cute costume. Congratulations!
いいかも、マジで。超可愛い。
It's really good. Super cute.
いや、でもさ、みなさん。今回はね、団長の新衣装お披露目だったから、みんなにはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど。
But you know, everyone. This time was my new costume reveal, so you guys wore your idol outfits.
みんなもさ、衣装持ってるじゃん？
But you guys have outfits too, right?
あ、そうだね。並んだりとかも今後したいな。
Ah, that's true. I want us to line up together in the future.
絶対やろう！並ぼう、並ぼう！お揃いしよう。
Definitely! Let's line up! Let's match.
そして、また歌って踊りたいなー！
And I want us to sing and dance again!
え、ちょっとそれって…それってもしや…あったかな？
Wait, could that be...? Could it be...?
はい！ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます！
Yes! And with that, I have lots of important announcements to make from here!
まず、ホロライブ3期生の単独ライブ！『hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 ～最強アイドル、推しかないでしょ！～』
First, Hololive 3rd Gen's solo live concert! "hololive 3rd Generation Live #KyururunDaisakusen ~SaikyouIdol, Oshikanaidesho!~"!
開催決定しております！
It's officially happening!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、日時ですが、2026年1月17日と18日の2日間にわたって開催されます！
Yes! As for the dates, it will be held over two days, on January 17th and 18th, 2026!
いや、会場はね、あのデッカい…Kアリーナ横浜となっております！
And the venue is that huge... K-Arena Yokohama!
昨日ね、なんと…まぁちょっと二次先行…ちょうどね、あ、終わっちゃったことなんですけど。
Actually, yesterday... well, the second round of presale tickets just ended.
お疲れ様。
Good job.
終わっちゃったことなんですけど、この後、先着の一般販売が、12月14日の…
Even though that ended, after this, the general first-come-first-served ticket sales will start on December 14th...
あ、正午？お昼の12時から…
Ah, noon? From 12:00 PM...
みたいな感じで、ちょっとね。まだ諦めずにチャンスがある。
And that's how it is. Don't give up just yet, there's still a chance.
大変だと思うけど。
It might be tough, but...
ぜひぜひ、あの、勝ち取ってください。
...you should definitely try to win!
お願いします！
Please do!
そして配信チケットはね、まだありますので。はい、絶賛発売中ですので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Also, streaming tickets are still available. Yes, they're currently on sale, so please check them out!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you!
そして、このライブを見てくださった方で「あ、買い忘れてる！」って人はいないと思うけど...
And for those watching this live, though I doubt anyone forgot to buy them...
グッズのね、先行販売と受注販売も、明日のね、えー、10月25日の18時までとなっております。
...the merchandise pre-orders and made-to-order sales are open until tomorrow, October 25th, at 6:00 PM.
おお、明日ね。
Oh, tomorrow!
そう。だから、ライブ会場でペンライト振りたいとか、配信見ながらペンライト振りたいよって人はぜひ！
Right. So, if you want to wave a penlight at the venue or while watching the stream...
えー、この機会をお見逃しなく！
...don't miss out on this opportunity!
現地行く人は、ぜひとも絶対絶対あった方が...
If you're going to the venue, you absolutely need one...
盛り上がりますよ！
...to hype things up!
お願いします！
Please do!
いやー、楽しみだね。
Man, I'm so excited.
めっちゃ楽しみ！
We're super excited!
団長もね、ちょっとおメイク変えたから。
I also updated my look a little bit.
そう、楽しみ！
Yes, we can't wait!
そんな感じで、せっかく来てくれたから。
Since you guys are here...
意気込みを一言ちょっと、聞こうかなと。
...how about a brief word on your enthusiasm?
一言ね。
Just a brief word.
誰から行く？
Who's going first?
じゃあ、マリンからこういう順番で。
Okay, starting with me, then in this order.
すごい良いこと言ってくれるんだろうな。
I'm sure she'll say something amazing.
頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best!
楽しむぞー！
Let's have fun!
みんなで盛り上げるぞー！
Let's hype everyone up together!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
光の速さで去っていった。みんな、ありがとう！
They left at the speed of light. Thank you, everyone!
てな感じで、えー、ここからはノエちゃんの告知に行きます。
And with that, let's move on to the announcements from me.
えー、まず1つ目は、こちら！
First up is this!
はい、今年も出ます。白銀ノエル誕生日記念2025のグッズ、わーい！
Yes, they're here again! Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration 2025 Merchandise! Yay!
えー、生誕グッズ、まずは、こちら。
First, let's look at this item.
はい、えー、「睡魔の世界へ！キラキラLEDアートパネル」。イラストはMyungYi先生が...
"Into the World of Sleep! Sparkly LED Art Panel" with illustrations by MyungYi-sensei...
はい、描いてくれました。ありがとうございます。いつもお世話になってます。らぶちらぶち。
...who drew this for me. Thank you so much! I'm always in your debt. Love you!
今回のね、ま、生誕ライブのステージと新衣装が、えー、テーマになっております。
The theme is based on this birthday live stage and my new outfit.
ま、LEDということで、こちら光るということでね。あの、ぜひお部屋に飾って、今回のライブを思い出して...
Since it features LEDs, it lights up. Please display it in your room and remember this live concert...
そう、思い出にしてください。
...as a wonderful memory.
はい、そして次は、こちら。
Okay, next up is this.
はい、「色んなノエちゃん♡ランダムマルチバンド」ということで、まるえり先生が描いてくれました。ありがとうございます。
"Various Noes♡ Random Multi-Bands" illustrated by Marueri-sensei. Thank you very much!
いや、色んなね、ノエちゃんがいますので、ま、ちょっと、どのノエちゃんがね、おうちに来るかなってちょっと楽しみにしつつ...
There are various versions of me. You can look forward to seeing which Noel comes to your home...
届いたらね、ま、マルチバンド、こちら、あの、お片付けの必需品となってます。
...and once they arrive, these multi-bands are essential for organizing.
えー、ノエちゃんも使っておりますので、あの、ぜひね、コードまとめるときとか、はい、実用性に富んでますので、使ってみてください。
I use them myself too. They're highly practical, especially for wrapping cords, so please try using them.
次は、えー、こちら。
Next is this.
はい、えー、「姫騎士ノエルぬいぐるみキーホルダー」ということで...
"Princess Knight Noel Plushie Keychain."
えー、昨年はね、あの、サンタさんのノエちゃんがぬいぐるみとして、はい、キーホルダー出たんですが...
Last year, we had a Santa Noel plushie keychain...
今回は、せっかく新衣装が出たので、えー、こちらでぬいぐるみキーホルダーを、えー、作りました。
...but since I got a new outfit, we made this plushie keychain with it this time.
あの、姫騎士として団員さんを守りますので、ぜひ肌身離さず、えー、持っててください。
I will protect my fans as a princess knight, so please keep it close to you at all times.
えー、次は、こちら。
Next is this.
はい、えー、「わんちょむ2wayネックピロー」ということで...
"Wanchomu 2-Way Neck Pillow."
ま、安眠に最適なネックピローなんですけど、今回は、なんとひっくり返すと...
It's a neck pillow perfect for a sound sleep, but this time, if you turn it inside out...
わんちょむになっている、ということで。
...it turns into Wanchomu!
ま、わんちょむはね、あの、今年から団長のおうちにお迎えしたわんちゃんのことなんですけど...
Wanchomu is the dog I welcomed into my home earlier this year...
えー、グッズにしちゃいました。
...and I turned him into merchandise!
え、ちょっとね、あの、ノエちゃんの、愛、あの、私情が入ってます、ということで、ぜひ団員さんのおうちにもお迎えください。
It definitely has some personal bias and love from me, so please welcome him into your home too.
え、最後にフルセットを見てみましょう、こちら。
Lastly, let's take a look at the full set here.
はい、今年もいっぱい、いっぱいグッズが出ました。いや、ぜひぜひ、あの、ゲットしてみてね。
Yes, we have plenty of merchandise again this year. Please make sure to get yours!
そして、このね、全部のフルセット特典があります。それはこちら。
And we also have bonuses for purchasing the full set. Here they are.
はい、ということで、フルセットを購入してくださった方にチェキ風ブロマイドカードついてきます。
Yes, those who purchase the full set will receive an instax-style photo card!
いや、とっても素敵。
It looks absolutely wonderful.
ま、イラストはね、MyungYi先生のイラストで、こちらに、えーと...
The illustration is by MyungYi-sensei, and on this...
あの、通常バージョンは箔押しの複製サインが、はい、あの、ぺたーってなるんですけど...
...the standard version will have a foil-stamped replica signature on it...
えー、数量限定バージョンは団長の直筆サインがついてきます。
...while the limited-quantity version will feature my actual handwritten signature!
あの、心を込めて書きますので、ぜひゲットしてみてくだい。
I will sign each one with all my heart, so please try to get it.
さらにね、さらにさらに、フルセットを購入してくれた方全員に特典ボイスもついてきちゃいます。
Furthermore, everyone who purchases the full set will also receive bonus voice tracks!
えー、フルセットのね、なんかちょっと欲しいって皆さん思ったんじゃないでしょうか。ぜひゲットしてみてください。ボイス...
I'm sure you all want to get the full set now, right? Please check it out! The voice tracks...
心を込めて書きました！よろしくお願いします！
I wrote it with all my heart! Please look forward to it!
えー、生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです。
And the birthday merch cart opens at 22:00!
皆さん、ぜひゲットしてください！おねがいしまーす。
Everyone, please be sure to get them! Thank you!
えー、さらにさらに、重大告知があります。
And there's even more! I have a major announcement.
なんとそれは、ドゥルルルルルル、はい！新曲があります！
And that is... *drumroll* ...Yes! I have a new song!
で、その新曲をね、発表するにあたって、なんと！
And, to announce this new song, what do you know!
ちょっと今回、ちょっとスペシャルな方からね、コメントを、ちょっといただいているみたいなんだけど、
We've actually received a video comment from a very special guest,
え、誰なんだろう、ちょっとノエルわかんないな。誰でしょうか？
but I have no idea who it is. I wonder who?
え？何？うわー、すっごいキラキラしてる。
Huh? What? Wow, it's so sparkly!
「こんまっするー！」／え？ちょっと待って、お、こんまっする。
"Kon-massuru!" / Huh? Wait, kon-massuru?
「白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！」／おめでとうございます。
"Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday!" / Thank you very much.
「そして団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？」／楽しんでますか？
"And to all the Order members, are you enjoying the stream?" / Are you enjoying it?
「大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。」
"I am Kiichiro Sato, the Governor of Oita Prefecture."
何？ちっちゃい！あ。
What? He's tiny! Ah.
「この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。」／あ、ありがとうございます。
"Congratulations on the announcement of your new song." / Ah, thank you so much.
「今回、私がノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただけることになりました。」／え？言ってくれるんですか？
"This time, I have been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song." / What? You're announcing it?
「それでは早速曲名を発表したいと思います。」／お願いします。
"So, without further ado, I would like to announce the song title." / Please do.
「その名も、VAVAVA！バーチャル大分。」
"Its title is... 'VAVAVA! Virtual Oita'!"
バーチャル大分、わーい！
Virtual Oita! Yay!
「そうですね、『バーチャル大分』と入っていますので、大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな。」／はい、そうです。
"Indeed, with 'Virtual Oita' in the title, it must be a song that lets you enjoy Oita virtually." / Yes, exactly!
「はい、大分のおすすめたくさんありますよ。」
"Yes! Oita has so many recommendations!"
「まずは何と言っても温泉です。」
"First and foremost, it has to be the hot springs!"
「大分県は源泉数、湧出量ともに全国一位ですから。」
"Oita Prefecture ranks first in Japan in both the number of hot spring sources and the volume of water discharge."
「他にも関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、おおいた和牛、からあげなんかの食の魅力も満載ですね。」／最高です。
"We also have a wealth of food attractions like Seki Horse Mackerel, Seki Mackerel, Kabosu Yellowtail, Oita Wagyu, and Karaage." / They are the best!
「ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです。」／はい。
"We hope everyone gets to experience them!" / Yes!
「ノエルさん、大分を代表して応援しちょんけん。」／はい。
"Noel-san, as a representative of Oita, we're rooting for you." / Yes.
「これからも大分県のPRを頼むけんな。」／え、ありがとうございます。
"Please continue to promote Oita Prefecture." / Ah, thank you so much!
「新曲、しんけん楽しみにしちょんけん。」／はい。
"We are truly looking forward to your new song." / Yes!
「それでは、おつまっする〜！」／おつ、おつまっする〜！
"Well then, Otsu-massuru!" / Otsu, Otsu-massuru!
あ、めじろんも！めじ、おつまっする、おつまっする、ということで、
Ah, Meijiron too! Otsu-massuru, Otsu-massuru! So...
まさかの意外や意外、
...what an absolute surprise!
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに、新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントをいただきました！ありがとうございます！
We received a new song title announcement and a supportive comment from the Governor of Oita Prefecture, Kiichiro Sato! Thank you so much!
あの、これ本当に、の、ノエルちゃんびっくりで、本当にこれサ、サプライズなんですけど、
I was seriously, seriously surprised by this. It was a complete surprise...
いや、本当にありがとうございます。まさか、こんな日が来るなんてっていうことで、
...but thank you so much. I never imagined a day like this would come!
いや、本当にすごい方から、あの、応援していただいて嬉しいですね。
I'm so happy to receive support from such an amazing person.
ちょ、団長、何が起こったのか最初わからず、
At first, I didn't even understand what was happening,
いや、しかも、めじろんも横にいて、あのね、あの、緑の。そう、いましたね。すごく可愛かったなと思います。
and Meijiron was right next to him too, you know, the green mascot. Yes, he was there. He was so cute.
あの本当にね、あの、あの、ずっと、あの団長、大分育ちで、
You see, Danchou actually grew up in Oita,
はい、あの大分の魅力をバーっと配信でね、あの個人的に、言ってるだけなんですけれど、
so I've just been talking about the wonders of Oita on stream purely on a personal level,
いや、本当に日頃ね、大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
but I'm really glad I've been sharing Oita's charm all this time!
あの、もちろんこれからも、あの個人的に、特に何か大きなことがあるわけではなく、あの、個人的に、はい。
Of course, from here on as well, just personally—not because of any official tie-up, but just on a personal level,
あの、団長、大分の魅力を伝えていきたいなと思いますので、
I want to keep sharing Oita's charm with everyone!
皆さんもまだ大分にいったことない人は、ぜひ大分いってみてください！いいところだよ！
So if any of you haven't been to Oita yet, please go visit! It's an amazing place!
はい、ということで、あの、新曲歌っちゃいたいと思います。
All right, with that said, I'd like to perform the new song now!
えー、聞いてください。VAVAVA！バーチャル大分！
Please listen to: 'VAVAVA! Virtual Oita'!
説明しよう。バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の東北部に位置する広大な大地。現実の大分県に限りなく近い地上の楽園。人はその地をバーチャル大分と呼ぶ！
Let me explain. Virtual Oita is a vast region located in northeastern Virtual Kyushu. A paradise on earth incredibly close to the real Oita Prefecture. People call that place Virtual Oita!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, released to the world,
バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
Virtual Oita, boiling the hot water.
君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running around Virtual Oita with you.
バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, BAM!
大分 どーん！
Oita, BAM!
君は降り立つ 魅惑の地獄の入り口 絶えず湯沸く 誘惑の地
You step foot into the entrance of the mesmerizing Hell, a land of temptation where hot water constantly boils.
海 かまど 白池 血の池
Umi, Kamado, Shiraike, Chinoike,
鬼石坊主 鬼山 竜巻 バーン！
Onishi Bozu, Oniyama, Tatsumaki, BAM!
とり天 とりめし やせうま 団子汁
Toriten, torimeshi, yaseuma, dangojiru.
中津からあげ 冷麺 関アジ 関サバ
Nakatsu karaage, reimen, Seki horse mackerel, Seki mackerel.
かぼす あつめし まだまだ入るよ
Kabosu, atsumeshi, there's room for more.
鉄の胃袋 大魔神
An iron stomach, Great Daimajin!
行こうぜ九重高原 湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highlands, a hot spring of rising steam.
高崎山に
At Mount Takasaki,
金鱗湖
Lake Kinrin,
青の洞門
Ao no Domon,
由布川渓谷
Yufugawa Valley,
進め
Go forward!
稲積水中鍾乳洞
Inazumi Underwater Cave!
果てしなき旅 魅力演奏
An endless journey, playing our charm,
たどり着く先 食べる弁当
Our destination, eating bento!
時空も超えた奇跡の土地
A miraculous land that transcends space and time!
バーチャル 大分
Virtual Oita!
いくぞー！
Let's go!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, releasing it to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, boiling up the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running all over Virtual Oita with you!
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, releasing it to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, eating it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running all over Virtual Oita with you!
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, boom!
よだきい よしゃあしい えらしい
Bothersome, meddlesome, lovely...
しんけん やわねえ ふうがわりぃ
...very, easy, strange...
なしか むげねぇ せせろしい
...why, pitiful, noisy!
だけどあんた今何しちょん？
But what are you doing right now?
説明しよう！
Let me explain!
バーチャル大分観光大使とは！
A Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador...
バーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち！
...is someone who holds a deep love for Virtual Oita...
その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在！
...and constantly shares its endless charm!
人はその大使の名を...
People call this ambassador...
バーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ！
...the Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador!
V-I-R-T-U-A-L I wanna be
ノエル 団長 観光大使
Noel, Leader, Tourism Ambassador!
V-I-R-T-U-A-L I wanna be
ノエル 団長 観光大使
Noel, Leader, Tourism Ambassador!
バババ バーチャル大分 世に放つ
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, releasing it to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 湯を沸かす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, boiling up the hot springs!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running all over Virtual Oita with you!
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
バーチャル大分 世に放つ
Virtual Oita, releasing it to the world!
バババ バーチャル大分 食べ尽くす
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, eating it all up!
君と バーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Running all over Virtual Oita with you!
バババ バーチャル大分 大分 どーん！
V-V-V-Virtual Oita, Oita, boom!
大分 どーん！
Oita, boom!
極楽、極楽～
Ah, this is heaven...
新曲MV公開、この後すぐ！
[New MV release, coming up next!]